BRENT RUSINOW

CONTACT

414-248-1080



brusinow@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/brusinow in



brentrusinowdev.com



EXPERTISE

Javascript jQuery Node.js **AJAX REST API interaction MVC Frameworks AngularJS** React.is Java HTML5 CSS3 ES₆ **Bootstrap** Ionic Firebase PostgreSQL/SQL MongoDB **NoSQL** Ruby Ruby on Rails Git & Github Photoshop/Illustrator

EDUCATION

Web Development Immersive, 2016
General Assembly

B.A., Economics, 2006Boston University

PROFILE

I am a creative-minded, solutions-driven software developer with a passion for intuitive design and function-focused web apps. My previous experience as a full-time touring musician informs everything that I do: from my ability to adapt and adjust plans quickly to finding efficient, concise solutions for challenging problems. My work ethic is reflected in my work, whether I am collaborating with my team to execute thoughtful user experiences or working on new projects to deepen my skillset.

RECENT PROJECTS

SISTERS WEBSITE (August 2016 – October 2016) AngularJS, Node.js, Firebase, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3

A website built for emerging Seattle band SISTERS before the release of their first full-length album. Built primarily using AngularJS/Express/Node.js/Firebase, the site features an online store incorporating Stripe's Orders API and a blog built with minimal outside libraries.

ROAD WARRIOR v2 (June 2016 – August 2016) AngularJS, Ionic, Cordova, Firebase, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3

Built with AngularJS and Ionic as a hybrid iPhone/Android app, Road Warrior aims to improve on the industry standard tour management solution by providing more user-focused features. Interacts with Yelp, Google Places, and Yahoo Weather to present recommended locations close to a venue and weather forecasts. Features realtime database interaction, multi-group support, and group chat.

ROAD WARRIOR v1 (April 2016) iQuery, Node.js, SQL(Postgres), JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3

The first version of my RoadWarrior app, this jQuery/Node.js app incorporates Yelp, Google Places, and the Open Weather API to make daily content easily available based on venue location and day of the week. Features multiple user levels to allow admin privileges when approving/denying a member access to a group.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

(June 2016 - Present)

Seattle, WA

Created a full stack website for an emerging Seattle band featuring full blog and store functionality with minimal outside libraries.

WEB DEVELOPMENT IMMERSIVE

(March 2016 - June 2016)

GENERAL ASSEMBLY Seattle, WA

- A top performing student in a full-time 12-week immersive course focusing on full stack development of responsive web apps.
- Created five separate projects showcasing a variety of technologies.

BASSIST/PRODUCTION MANAGER

(June 2011- March 2016)

ALLEN STONE Seattle, WA

- Traveled the world, performing 200+ shows per year supporting major label artist.
- Responsibilities included coordinating equipment requirements for tours/festivals, advancing stage configurations, and assembling hired horn sections around the world.
- Appeared on The Tonight Show, David Letterman, Jimmy Kimmel Live, Conan, and Ellen. During this time also
 performed with Macklemore, Dispatch, OAR, and members of the Dave Matthews Band, Bon Jovi, Jack's
 Mannequin, and Soulive.

FREELANCE BASSIST

(June 2008 - June 2011)

Boston, MA and Seattle, WA

- Created and maintained personal website through use of Wordpress, HTML, and CSS.
- Incorporated a paid download system for online lesson content through additional Wordpress libraries.

ADMIN OPERATIONS MANAGER (June 2008 – September 2009)

MIT DEPARTMENT OF URBAN STUDIES Cambridge, MA

 Launched and maintained a PHP-based web platform with integrated message board and thesis repository to better align team projects.